When the Air Force assigned Jimmy Garrett to a top secret project,
he didn't know what he was in for. Neither did they.
Project X is a drama, comedy film directed by Jonathan Kaplan.
A young inductee into the military is given the task of looking after
some chimpanzees used in the mysterious 'Project X'.
Getting to know the chimps fairly well, he begins to suspect there
is more to the secret project than he is being told.
Jimmy Garrett, played by Matthew Broderick.
Teri Macdonald, played by Helen Hunt.
Virgil, played by Willie.
Dr. Carroll (as Bill Sadler), played by William Sadler.
Robertson, played by Johnny Ray McGhee.
Sgt. Krieger, played by Jonathan Stark.
Project X is a 1987 American science fiction comedy
drama film produced by Walter F.
Parkes and Lawrence Lasker, directed by Jonathan Kaplan, and
starring Matthew Broderick and Helen Hunt.
The plot revolves around a USAF Airman (Broderick) and a graduate student (Hunt) who
are assigned to care for chimpanzees used in a secret Air Force project.
The film explores themes of chimp, laboratory, chimpanzee,
sign languages, secret military program.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.